来  小查莉  惹了麻烦时怎么说
Okay, Charlie, what do you say when you get in trouble?
噢喔
Uh-oh.
噢  小查莉刚刚说了句噢喔是吗
Oh, Charlie just made an uh-oh?
我才给你换了尿布啊
I just changed you.
不  小查莉什么也没做
No, Charlie didn't do anything.
我在给她声音取样罢了
I'm just sampling her.
"取样"指我把她说的每一句录制下来
"sampling" means I'm recording all the words she says.
以便之后回放
So I can play them back.
呵  我们过去也玩这个
Oh, we used to do that.
我们它把叫做磁带录音
We called it tape-recording.
来听听
Check it out.
我的  是的
Mine, yes,
不是  饼干  香蕉
no,cookie, Nana.
爸爸  你答应过我今天陪我练车的
Dad, you promised you'd take me driving today.
实话告诉你吧  我答应了一堆我办不到的事情
To be fair, I promise a lot of things I don't deliver on.
没错  可你不能把这事儿推了
Yeah, but you can't keep putting this off.
我三天后就要考驾照了  你一次也没陪过我
My driver's test is in three days,and you haven't taken me out once.
是  我知道  我知道  你跟我说过了
No, I know, I know.You explained it all to me.
那时我还在厕所里翻杂志啊
While I was trying to read in the bathroom.
你还隔着厕所门跟爸爸说的啊
You were outside the door while dad was in the bathroom?
瞧瞧我多渴望驾驶
That's how much I want it.
鲍伯你就带她去吧
Bob, take her driving already.
行  好吧  走
All right, fine.Let's go.
我早告诉过你我一出厕所准没好事
Boy, I tell you, nothing good ever happens when I leave the bathroom.
拜拜  拜  拜  拜拜
Bye-bye.Bye... bye... bye-bye.
-这是什么声音  -只不过怕你不说再见
- What's that?- Just in case you don't make it back.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
生活搞得一团糟
<i>Today's all burnt toast</i>
就要迟到  爸爸在叫
<i>Running late, and dad jokes</i>
我左脚的鞋子有没有人看到
<i>Has anybody seen my left shoe</i>
■
翻译： 没有昵称
我闭上眼  咬口早餐
<i>I close my eyes, take a bite</i>
跳上车子  放声大笑
<i>Grab a ride, laugh out loud</i>
哎呀  老爸  鞋子就在房顶上
<i>There it is up on the roof</i>
■
校订  后期： line  追忆似水年华
我也曾这样生活  我已经顺利走过
<i>I've been there, I've survived</i>
所以听取我的建议
<i>So just take my advice</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby, </i>
世界有很多疯狂无奈
<i>Things are crazy</i>
可是我知道你会有美好未来
<i>But I know your future is bright</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
不要怀疑
<i>There is no maybe</i>
一切终会如你所愿
<i>Everything turns out all right</i>
生活有悲有喜
<i>Sure life is up and down</i>
但是请相信我  坚持就有好结果
<i>But trust me, it comes back around</i>
你会喜欢将来的你
<i>You're gonna love who you turn out to be</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby.</i>
查莉成长日记  第一季第二十六集（本季完）
Good Luck Charlie  S01E26 Driving Mrs.Dabney
P.J  你打算送泰迪什么生日礼物
P.J., what did you get Teddy for her birthday?
-生日  -你姐姐就要16岁了
- Birthday? - Your sister's turning 16.
我们明晚给她办个惊喜派对
We're having a surprise party for her tonight.
嗯  我看一定能惊喜到她
Well, it's working,
因为我已经被惊喜到了
'cause I'm surprised.
派对7点开始
The party starts at 7:00.
你得给她份礼物或准备点什么
You have to get her a present,and something nice.
-那么就送  -不许再送袜子玩偶
- How about...? - Not another sock puppet.
你也得送她生日礼物
You have to get her something too.
噢  噢  我走错地方了吗
Whoa whoa, what did I just walk into?
妈妈说我们得给泰迪买份生日礼物
Mom says we have to buy Teddy a birthday present.
送条狗如何
What about a dog?
我打赌她一定喜欢狗
I bet she'd like a dog.
严肃点儿  你得真的为她买点什么
I'm serious. You have to get her something.
送条狗如何  我打赌她一定喜欢狗
What about a dog? I bet she'd like a dog.
盖比  我们家进了狗吗
Gabe, is there a dog in my house?
也许吧
Maybe.
是它尾随我进的家门的 妈妈
He followed me home, mom.
我们能把它留下吗
Can we keep him?
不行  我跟你说了无数次了
No. I've told you 100 times
屋里不准养狗
I do not want a dog in this house.
拜托了妈妈
Mom, please.
马马
Horsy.
不  宝贝儿  这是狗狗
No, honey. It's actually a doggie.
它刚刚来了句马声马气的噢喔
Who just made a horsy-sized uh-oh.
抱歉泰迪  我最终主意已定
Sorry, Teddy.I've made my decision and it's final.
爸爸  这太不公平了
Dad, that's so unfair.
妈妈  爸爸不让我拿驾照
Mom, dad says I can't get my license.
-什么  为什么不能  -因为她还不够格
- What? Why not?- Because she's not ready.
噢不  我教练觉得我能行  他认为我相当棒
Well, my driving instructor thinks I am. He says I'm doing great.
你教练为公立学校开车
The man works for the public schools.
没什么钱过日子才这么说的
He's got nothing to live for.
妈妈  你能说两句吗
Mom, can you say something?
宝贝儿泰迪  真的抱歉了
Teddy honey, I'm sorry,
不过你爸爸在家倒是没什么发言权
But your father has a very small area of authority...
可不幸的是
And unfortunately for you,
教你们孩子开车他还是有权的
Teaching you kids to drive is part of it.
那还有什么是有权的
So what else is in that area?
烧烤
Barbecuing.
没了
That's it.
爸爸  拜托了
Dad, please.
我真的超想在16岁那天拿到驾照
I really want to get my license the day I turn 16.
瞧  这压根不可能  不是吗
Look, it's not gonna happen, all right?
暂时没有什么驾驶机会了  等另行通知再说
So until further notice,there's gonna be no driving.
嘿抱歉  钥匙交出来行吗
Sorry. Can I have the keys, please?
给你
Here.
真不想相信我在厕所外站了那么久还是不行
I can't believe I stood outside the bathroom door for this.
嘿
Hey.
你是支持我的  对吧
You're on my side, right?
-亲爱的  -什么
- Honey. - Yeah?
我怎么会对着一条狗说话
Why am I talking to a dog?
它尾随盖比进的家门
He followed Gabe home.
不过别担心  我把它弄得干干净净
But don't worry.I made it very clear.
我们不会留它下来的
We are not keeping him.
嘿  你知道吗
Hey, you know something?
它有那么点让我想到你的斯坦叔叔
He kind of reminds me of your Uncle stan.
-什么  -瞧这湿湿的鼻子和充血的眼睛
- What? - The wet nose and the bloodshot eyes.
拜托  他
Come on, he...
好吧  我也发觉了
Oh, now I see it.
P.J  问你个问题
P.J., I have a question.
爸爸教你开车的时候很抓狂吗
Was dad out of control when he was teaching you how to drive?
没啊 不  他脾气很好
No no, he was very mellow.
那么他到底怎么了
Then what is his problem?
嗯  因为脱发  杀虫谋生
Well, hair loss, kills bugs for a living...
答案可真多
There's so much to choose from.
好吧  不管为什么  他为什么拿我当出气筒
Well, whatever it is, why did he have to take it out on me?
我怎么知道  或许你开得太烂
I don't know.Maybe you're a bad driver.
不  我开得很好
No, I'm a good driver.
我是考驾照这群人中唯一的一个
I was the only kid in driver's ed.
看了暴力凶杀片儿没有呕吐的
Who didn't barf during the splattered brains movie.
正好我也有问题要问你
Actually I have a question for you.
我有个朋友快16了
I have a friend who is turning 16.
我得给她买个生日礼物
And I have to buy her a birthday present.
嗯  明白了
Mm, well
我知道你朋友一定不想要袜子玩偶
I know your friend wouldn't want a sock puppet.
好吧
Okay.
话说  她到底会想要什么
Well, what would she want?
嗯
Well,
她或许喜欢靴子
She'd probably like boots,
像商场里很炫的店里的那种
Like from that cool store at the mall,
但别买黑底紫色流苏的
But not the black ones with the purple trim.
她已经有了双
She already has those.
我只是瞎猜罢了
I'm just guessing.
噢  嗨  达布尼太太
Oh hi, Mrs. Dabney.
我看见你们家的人弄了条狗来
I see you people have a dog now.
呃  我最近不错  多谢关心  你呢
Oh, I'm doing fine, thanks.How are you?
我有事得和你说清楚
Let me explain something to you.
你们的狗让我家的猫神经紧张
Your dog makes my Cat nervous.
我家猫一神经紧张  我就跟着神经紧张
And when my Cat gets nervous, I get nervous.
我一神经紧张  达布尼先生就神经紧张
And when I get nervous, Mr. Dabney gets nervous.
那接下来如何
Then what happens?
达布尼先生会住到他妈妈家
Mr. Dabney goes to stay with his mother.
因此你们养狗看起来也没那么坏
So this dog thing is not entirely bad.
行了  我们谈话结束了
All right, we're done here.
噢  达布尼太太  先别走
Oh, Mrs. Dabney,before you go,
呃  我需要些练车的时间
Um, I need some more practice hours.
在我拿到驾照之前
Before I take my driver's test,
你需要司机的话  我愿意给你当
So if you ever need a chauffeur, I'm your girl.
那么走吧
Let's go.
就现在
Right now?
我有一堆事要做
I've got a bunch of errands to run.
如果你来开  我就能在手机上玩猜字游戏了
And if you drive, I can play word jumble on my cell phone.
其实我开车时一直玩  只不过这样合法罢了
Actually I do that anyway,but this way it's legal.
这家店怎么只有女孩
This store only has girls in it.
没错
Yeah.
好吧泰迪姐鞋码多大
So what's Teddy's shoe size?
我怎么知道
I don't know.
你连她鞋码都不知道
You don't know her shoe size?
我甚至不知道她的中间名
I don't know her middle name.
噢  小子  那我们怎么给她买鞋
Well, dude, how are we supposed to buy her shoes?
等会儿
Wait a minute.
泰迪上周误穿了你的运动鞋  对不对
Teddy wore your sneakers by mistake last week, right?
-没错  -这就是说你们穿一样大的鞋
- Yes. - That means you're the same size.
来  试试看
Here, try these on.
噢  不
Oh no.
我才不穿女孩子的鞋呢
I am not putting on girl boots.
来啊  拜托了
Oh, come on.
它们和你穿的女式T恤真配
They'll look good with that girl shirt you're wearing.
这上面不是小马  这是公马
It's not a pony.It's a stallion.
好吧  我只试穿两秒
Fine, I'll put them on for two seconds.
在给我妹妹买鞋呢
Buying boots for my sister.
说来好笑  她和我弟弟鞋码一样
Funny story... she and my brother have the same size feet.
幸亏她没想买内衣  对不对
Good thing she didn't want underwear, right?
噢  再见了
Okay, see you.
唉  合适的
Okay, they fit.
噢  兄弟  等等  你得站起来看看
Whoa, hold on, dude.You've gotta stand up,
走一圈看看  合适吗
Walk around, make sure they're comfortable.
拜托
Come on.
哇  你的腿穿这鞋看上去真奇妙
Wow, those do wonders for your legs.
好了  够了
Okay, that's enough.
这鞋脱不下来
They won't come off.
怎么会  让我试试
What?Let me try.
你的脚怎么会那么胖
Why are your feet so fat?
我的脚不胖  这叫健壮
They're not fat.They're husky.
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
噢  只有一件事要做
Well, there's only one thing to do.
-你在给谁打电话呢  -没谁
- Who are you calling? - No one.
我在拍你穿女孩靴的照片
I'm taking a picture of you in girl boots.
这灯一点儿也没变绿
The light's not getting any greener.
我明白  是我前面那辆车一直挡着不动
I know, but the car in front of me hasn't moved yet.
这就是快速驾驶课
Here's a quick driving lesson.
快醒醒  老头子
Wake up, grandpa!
对不起  是她在乱叫  不是我
Sorry, that was her, not me.
噢看啊  老爷爷把第一名的位置让道给我们了
Oh look, grandpa's telling us we're number one.
不  他才不是呢  他
No, he's not.He's...
我知道他在干什么了
I know what he's doing.
看样子我们现在得掉头回去了  是不是
So we should probably head home now, right?
再多停一站  博尔德  我要见我的姐姐
Just one more stop... boulder.I want to see my sister.
博尔德  可那在山区啊
Boulder?That's in the mountains.
噢  你只拿平地驾驶证吗
Oh, you got one of those flat-land-only driving permits?
不是啦  只不过我得在7点之前回家
No, it's just I have to be home by 7:00.
噢  我们或许得停下来加油了
Oh, and we should probably stop for gas.
这车没油也能开100米
In this car you can drive 100 miles on empty.
需要油了我再告诉你
I'll tell you when we need gas.
现在我们得加油了
Now we need gas.
没错  可有个问题
Yeah, just one problem...
我们现在前不着村后不着店
We're in the middle of nowhere.
而且快要下雨的样子
And it looks like rain.
啊
Agh!
而且窗外还有个疯女人
And there's a crazy woman outside my window.
所以算起来我们有三个问题
So actually we got three problems.
你好啊
Hello.
隔着那么点窗缝说话有点困难
Kinda hard to talk with the window open just a crack.
抱歉
Sorry.
你们俩在这儿干什么
What are y'all doing over here?
我们没油了
We're out of gas.
噢  你们今天真幸运
Well, this is your lucky day.
沿着路往下开一会就有加油站
There's gas and such down the road a spell.
噢  一会儿是多远
Oh, how far is a spell?
50米
50 miles.
当然了  我这儿有一加仑的油
Of course, I got a gallon of gas right here.
太好了  多少钱
Great.How much is it?
50元
50 bucks.
山中疯女一定有诈
The mountain lady's got an angle.
我还有口香糖  薄荷糖  杂志
I also got gum, mints, magazines.
我还能让你们跟上贾斯汀比伯的资讯潮流
I could keep you up to date on all things Justin bieber.
噢
Oh.
小查莉
Charlie.
小查莉  把胶带给妈咪
Charlie, hand mommy the tape.
好吧
Fine.
成了6岁生日派对了
It'll just be a "sweet 6" party.
你在画什么呀
What are you drawing?
在画一幅美丽的图片吗
Are you making a pretty picture?
你想干吗  坏狗
What do you want, dog?
马马
Horsy.
你在干吗
What are you doing?
你到底在干吗  你不能呆在这儿
What are you doing?You cannot be here.
你还是有点可爱的嘛
You're kind of sweet.
好啦  只许呆一分钟
Okay, just for a minute.
你一点儿不坏  不是吗
You're not such a bad dog, are you?
完全不坏嘛  你是好狗狗
No, you're a good dog.
给你取个名儿叫小甜派吧
I'm gonna call you sweetie-pie
因为你长得真像个小甜派
'cause you're a sweetie-pie.
-妈咪  -查莉  现在别给我
- Mommy. - Charlie, not now.
好的
Yes.
妈妈  我们遇上大麻烦了
Mom, we have got a big problem.
噢  没错
Oh, you sure do.
靴子和短裤不配嘛
Those boots do not go with those shorts.
你在挑战我最后的耐心
You are working my last nerve.
她可真麻烦
She is a handful.
这儿看起来似曾相识不是吗
Does any of this look familiar?
看上去像我们10分钟之前开过的路
Looks like the same road we drove down 10 minutes ago.
这么做我刚才一直在绕圈子
So I'm just going in circles.
你居然也不说什么
And you didn't want to say anything?
我觉得这种令人不快的沉默胜过千言万语
I thought my annoyed silence was speaking volumes.
好吧
Okay.
唉  我们迷路了
Well, we're lost.
我们需要张地图  你有地图吗
And we need to look at a map.Do you have a map?
手机上有  但要关了猜字游戏才看得到
On my cell phone.But I'd have to turn off my word jumble.
好吧
Okay.
你刚刚在干什么
What did you do now?
我觉得我们好像陷入坑里了
I think we're in some kind of hole.
没错  我们中的一个得下去并推车
Well, then one of us is gonna have to get out and push...
16岁的那个请下车
The one of us who's 16.
我还没满16呢
I'm not 16 yet.
-下车  -好吧
- Get out. - Okay.
行了  到位了  试着往前开开啊
Okay, hit it, but try to go...
慢点行不
Slow.
唉  再试回  但这次
Okay, go again, but this time.
试着开得再慢一点啊
Try to go a little bit slower.
天呐
Oh.
噢  真是好极了
Well, this would be a great time.
山中疯女拿些裙子来也可以赚翻了
For the mountain lady to come by with some skirts.
嘿  甜心
Hey, sweetie.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi.- Hi.
我想我的狗应该在你们这儿
I think you found my dog.
呃  我们这儿没有狗
Um, we don't have a dog here.
你确定
Really?
我在这个传单上看到了你们家的地址啊
I found this flyer with your address on it.
那一定是印错了  这儿没狗  再见
Must be a misprint.No dog. Bye-bye.
妈妈  妈妈  我能和你说两句吗
Mom, mom, can I talk to you for a minute?
嘿  我们马上就来
Hi, we'll be right with you.
好的
Okay.
听着  妈妈  我们得诚实
Look, mom, we've got to do the right thing here.
如果你想要狗  我们可以另买一条
If you want a dog,we can get you another one.
我不要其他的狗
I don't want another dog.
我只要我的小甜派
I want my sweetie-pie.
妈妈 他已经有家了
Mom, he already has a family.
一个爱他关心他的家
Who loves him and misses him.
他需要回家
He needs to go home.
我明白
I know.
再见  小甜派
Goodbye, sweetie-pie.
我永远不会忘记你
I will never forget you.
温斯顿
Winston!
谢谢你
Thank you.
客气
You're welcome.
我真为你骄傲
I'm very very proud of you.
我们来点儿冰激凌如何
Now how about we go get you some ice cream?
-好吧  -好  走吧
- Okay.- Yes, come on.
嘿  大家都注意啦  泰迪来了
Oh, you guys, Teddy's here.
都藏起来  快藏起来
Everybody hide.Hide.
给你惊喜
Surprise!
噢天呐
Aww.
噢  好吧
Oh, okay.
我知道你们在想什么
I know what you're thinking...
泰迪啥都能穿
Teddy can wear anything.
嗯  呃
Oh, um...
我干吗不去洗洗
Why don't I go clean up.
我们30分钟后再给我惊喜  好不好
And we'll try this again in 30 minutes, okay?
噢对了  你们真赞
Oh, one more thing...you guys!
-蛋糕不错  妈妈  -商店里买来的
- Great cake, mom.- I got it at the store.
明白  所以才说"蛋糕不错  妈妈"
I know. That's why I said "great cake, mom."
爸爸  你在外面做什么呢
Dad, what are you doing out here?
思考罢了  派对开心吗
Just thinking.Are you enjoying your party?
是的  棒极了  太谢谢你们了
Yeah, it's awesome.Thank you so much.
爸爸  有些事想和你说说
Dad, I have to tell you something.
你一下午都在和达布尼太太开车
You spent the afternoon driving with Mrs. Dabney.
你从我这句"有些事想和你说说"判断出来的吗
You got all that from "I have to tell you something"?
不是  其实我知道这事儿
No, actually I got all that.
当达布尼太太把你裙子还过来的时候
From when Mrs. Dabney returned your skirt.
现在你知道为什么我说我不想让你开车了吧
Now you know I told you I didn't want you driving.
我知道  抱歉
I know.I'm sorry.
噢  好吧
All right, you know what?
明早再聊这个吧
Let's just talk about this tomorrow.
-爸爸  我真的开得不错  -泰迪
- Dad, I'm a really good driver.- Teddy.
不  可你为什么待我与P.J不同
No, why are you treating me different than P.J.?
你教他开车时一点也不生气
You didn't freak out on him when he was learning how to drive.
因为教P.J开车与教你完全不同
Because teaching P.J.to drive was a completely different thing.
-为什么  -没有什么因为
- Why? - Because it was.
-为什么啊  -因为他是P.J
- Why? - Because he's P.J.
你是我宝贝女儿
You're my little girl.
学会开车意味着离开
Driving means leaving.
一旦你关上车门
And once you get in that car,
你就离我们而去了
You go.
爸爸
Dad.
瞧瞧  真是抱歉啊  不是吗
Look, I'm sorry, okay?
你快回去继续你派对的事吧
You've got your party and stuff going on.
我真是不应该说这些扫兴话的
I shouldn't be talking about this stuff.
爸爸  想来真伤心
Dad, it's sad to think.
总有一天你的孩子们会全部离开家
All your kids are gonna leave someday.
哈哈  实话来说
Well, actually to be perfectly honest,
对于P.J
With P.J.
我还有点儿担心他赖着不走呢
I'm kind of worried he's never gonna leave.
嗯  也对
Yeah, well,
多往好处想啦
We'll hope for the best.
爸爸  我想让你明白即使
Dad, I want you to know that even though
我有一天关上车门开走了
I'm gonna get in that car and drive away someday,
我也一定会开回来的
I'm also gonna drive back home.
没错  多半带着一堆换洗衣物
Yeah, probably with a trunkful of laundry.
是啊
Yeah.
下面有请P.J和盖比
And now P.J. And Gabe.
给你送上生日惊喜
Have a special birthday surprise for you.
首先请允许我介绍
But first let me introduce.
侦探小查查
Snoop Charlie char.
泰迪  这个节目是为你特别准备的
Teddy, this one's for you.
-准备好了吗  -嗯
- Ready?  - Yep.
预备  齐
Ready, set, go.
我们出门为大姐购置靴子
we went to buy boots for a special sister
可靴子卡在我的脚上  磨得我一脚水泡
but they got stuck and now I got a blister
可我们身无分文  时间又紧迫
we were out of money, we were out of time
所以我们和查莉一起  为你送上这首说唱
so we dressed up with Charlie and busted out a rhyme
你十六岁了  马上就要出去闯荡了
you're 16 now, gonna move out soon
再过几年  你的房间就归我了
in a few more years I'm gonna get your room
我们的祝福语不多  但是希望你能知道
that's all we got, but we hope you know
无论你身处何处  我们与你同在
that we're with you, Teddy, not matter where you go
-泰迪  泰迪  -生日快乐
- <I> Teddy, Teddy</I>  - Happy Birthday..
嗨  小查莉  瞧瞧我们俩
Well, Charlie, here we are,
邓肯姐妹在姐姐16岁生日上录视频呢
The Duncan sisters on my 16th birthday.
能说句"祝泰迪生日快乐"吗
Can you say, "happy birthday, Teddy"?
不行  好吧
No? Okay.
没事儿  重在情谊嘛
Well, it's the thought that counts.
总之  我能拿到驾照真是太棒了
Anyway, the big news is I got my driver's license,
这意味着我想去哪儿完全自由了
Which means I now have total freedom to go wherever I want.
泰迪  我想让你去商店买些东西回来
Teddy, I need you to pick up some things at the store.
买东西时别忘了加油
And while you're at it,the car needs gas.
还有去接盖比  我可不想接他
And pick up gabe just 'cause I don't wanna.
果然自由啊
Total freedom.
能祝我好运吗  小查莉
Can you wish me good luck, Charlie?
重在情谊嘛
It's the thought that counts.
我们到那儿了吗
Are we there yet?
你看见大峡谷了吗
Did you see a grand canyon?
我想上厕所
I need to go to the bathroom.
我告诉过你叫你走之前上的
I told you to go before we left.
-可我那时不想上  -我们还没到呐
- I didn't have to go then.  - Are we there now?
请出示驾驶证件  小姐
License and registration, ma'am.
盖比  是我  泰迪
Gabe, it's me... Teddy.
十分抱歉
I'm sorry.
请出示驾驶证件  泰迪
License and registration, Teddy.
■
查莉成长日记第一季剧终  期待第二季！
算你幸运
You got lucky.